字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
Hey, you all right?
喂，你沒事吧？
Who's that?
那是誰？
He's gigantic.
他好高大
What about our duel?
我們的決鬥呢？
What did he say? A duel?
他說什麼？決鬥？
The duel!
決鬥！
Get your ass up!
現在不是睡覺的時候！
Hey, he got up!
喂，他站起來了
He didn't die!
他竟然還活著！
You can still fight.
看來你還能打
Take time to recover.
我會給你時間處理傷口
Don't mock me! Come at me now!
別嘲笑我，繼續打！
No, you certainly can't fight like that.
不是啊，你這樣沒辦法再打了
Shut up! I don't need your pity--
閉嘴！我不需要你的同…
What did I tell you?
看吧，我是怎麼說的？
Hey, old man!
喂，大叔！
Stop!
站住！
Let him go.
讓他去吧
Bring me a chair.
拿張椅子過來
Let me look at it.
讓我看看
Back off, geezer.
光頭，滾開
See to your own injuries.
你管好自己的傷勢就好
Just let me see.
讓我看看就是了
Don't touch me!
別碰我！
Don't get so worked up.
不要動不動就生氣
That's a bad habit.
這是你的壞毛病
Use your mind.
動動腦筋
Think. What must you do to win this duel?
想想現在要怎麼做才能打贏
It's been a while since I've had so much fun, Thorfinn.
我好久沒玩得這麼開心了，托爾芬
As promised, I'll tell you a story.
按照約定，我說故事給你聽吧
I'll tell you about your father, Thors.
我來說說你父親托爾茲的故事
So you know about the Jomsvikings.
你知道約姆戰士團吧？
Thors and I were both battalion commanders.
我和托爾茲都是軍團裡的大隊長
Even among us, Thors was clearly the strongest.
但托爾茲是我們之中最強的
The Jomsvikings only take the best warriors.
他在只收強者的約姆戰士團中
But even then, he earned his nickname the Troll.
有著“戰鬼”的外號
Our supreme commander Sigvaldi took a liking to him,
我們的首領席古瓦帝非常欣賞他
and gave his daughter's hand to Thors.
所以將女兒許配給托爾茲
That was your mother, Helga.
她就是你的母親海爾加
The leader of the Jomsvikings
約姆戰士團的首領是我外公？
That's right.
沒錯
And my older brother.
他也是我哥哥
In other words, I am your great-uncle.
也就是說，我是你的外叔公
He's related to the commander?
他是老大的親戚？
Unbelievable!
不會吧…
Our last battle together was at Hjörungavágr in Norway.
他參與的最後一場戰爭 是挪威的霍倫加瓦格之戰
Our side was losing.
我們戰敗了
During the battle,
在海戰中
Thors fell into the water and never resurfaced.
托爾茲落海後就沒有再浮上來
I wept.
我當時還哭了
I had planned to defeat him someday with my own two hands.
我本來打算親手打敗他的
The last time I saw him was in Jomsborg,
我最後一次見到他是在約姆斯伯爾格
about three months after his funeral.
他的葬禮三個月後
-Then he got scared and pissed himself. -Are you serious?
-然後那傢伙嚇到尿褲子 -真的假的？
Come out. The watchmen are gone.
巡邏的人走了，可以出來了
Hey!
喂！
Are you petty thieves?
你們是小偷嗎？
Do you know that this is the home of battalion leader Thors?
你們知道這裡是戰士團幹部 托爾茲的家嗎？
Thorkell.
托魯克爾
Normally, I'd let petty thieves go.
我平常是不管小偷的
But ever since I just lost my good friend,
但我剛失去一位好哥們
I've been in a bad mood.
所以最近心情很糟
Thors?
托爾茲？
You…
你…
Well, what do you know!
搞什麼？
Where have you been?
你到底跑哪去了？
We held a funeral for you!
我們還幫你辦了葬禮！
All right, already. Calm down, Thorkell.
好，冷靜點，托魯克爾
I'm sorry for worrying you.
抱歉讓你擔心了
Oh, now I can see, that's Helga?
仔細看才發現，妳不是海爾加嗎？
Why are the two of you wearing the matching clothes of beggers?
你們夫妻倆怎麼都穿得一身髒兮兮？
Uncle Thorkell…
托魯克爾叔叔…
I knew it.
我就知道
You couldn't die falling into the sea.
你不可能會因為落海就死掉
I'm sorry, Uncle, but we--
抱歉，叔叔，我們…
Have you seen my brother? Not yet? All right, I'll rouse him for you.
見過我哥了嗎？還沒嗎？
Thorkell.
托魯克爾
-Please listen to me. -Okay!
-你聽我說 -好！
We have much to discuss. Let's talk inside.
我們進屋裡慢慢聊吧
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
I will not go see the leader.
我不會去見首領
We are leaving this place.
我們要離開這裡
Why?
去做什麼？
Do it tomorrow.
明天再做啊
You've just come home.
你才剛回家
I am leaving town
我們要離開這裡
and the Jomsvikings.
離開約姆戰士團
Could you forget that you ever saw us tonight?
你能忘記今晚見到我們的事嗎？
What? Is this a joke?
什麼？這是在開玩笑嗎？
Continue telling the story of my death.
你就當我死掉了
Please, Thorkell.
拜託了，托魯克爾
I don't follow you.
我不懂你在說什麼
Why suddenly now?
為什麼這麼突然？
I've made a decision.
我已經決定了
I won't fight anymore.
我不會再戰鬥了
Like I said, I don't follow you!
我說了
It's hard to believe that you're afraid of death.
你該不會因為差點死掉就怕了吧？
My brother thinks of you as his successor.
我哥都把你當成接班人了
I'm sorry.
對不起
You're tired, right?
你累了吧？
Just eat something and sleep for the night.
吃點東西，睡一覺再說吧
I've come to understand…
我後來明白了
what it means to be a true warrior.
什麼才是真正的戰士
That is why
所以
we cannot stay here.
我們不能繼續待在這裡
You know the code.
你知道我們的規矩
Those who leave without a pardon are sentenced to death.
沒經過首領允許 就擅自離開的人只能處以死刑
This is the warrior capital.
這裡是戰士之都
You're made only for fighting. Where would you go?
你只會戰鬥，還有哪裡可以去？
Somewhere that's not here.
只要不是這裡就行
Thors.
托爾茲
It will be fine.
不會有事的
Stay back.
退後吧
Take care, Thorkell.
保重，托魯克爾
Where is your sword?
你的劍呢？
I don't need it.
我不需要
When I came to, Thors and his family were gone.
我醒來後，托爾茲他們已經走了
Fifteen years later, I learned that Thors had died for real.
15年後，才傳來托爾茲真正的死訊
I've thought about him for 15 years
這15年來，我一直想著他的事
and realized the life and death of the body is not what matters.
我發現肉體的生或死根本不重要
What's important to a warrior is the soul and where it goes.
對戰士來說，真正重要的是 靈魂以及它的所在之處
Thors's soul has gone far away.
托爾茲的靈魂去了遠方
To a place that I don't know.
去了我還無法理解的地方
To a place that I still can't reach.
去了我還到不了的地方
To somewhere that's not here.
去了一個不是這裡的地方
I'm sure he has become a true warrior there.
我相信他在那裡 已經成為真正的戰士了
Thorfinn,
托爾芬
what kind of life did he live in Iceland?
他在冰島的生活如何？
Tell me.
告訴我吧
What?
什麼？
But I told you!
我都跟你說了
Shut up! I don't care!
煩死了，我才不管
How selfish.
小氣鬼
Besides, you probably won't tell because you can't.
我看你不是不想講，而是說不出來吧
I can tell by your eyes.
看你的眼神就知道
You lack the light that was in his eyes.
你沒有他那種不可思議的光芒
What'd you say?
你說什麼？
You're afraid we're going to find out you didn't learn anything from Thors.
你怕我們會發現 你沒有從托爾茲身上學到任何東西
Wait.
等等
Let me go or I'll kill you first!
放開我，不然我先殺了你
You will lose if you go after him now.
如果用普通的方式戰鬥，你一定會輸
What'd I say?
看吧？
Your victory or defeat is my life or death.
你的勝負攸關我的生死
I will teach you…
所以我來告訴你
how to defeat that monster.
該怎麼打敗那個怪物吧
Don't spout nonsense, geezer!
別胡說八道，光頭
If you knew that, then why didn't you fight him?
如果你知道方法 那之前怎麼不跟他打？
War and chess are different, boy.
小子，戰鬥可不像下棋
The war doesn't end when the leader is taken.
不是把老大幹掉就會贏的
But this time is different.
但這次不一樣
If you win, he said he'll let us go.
你贏的話，他答應會放我們走
He takes his honor seriously.
他很重視身為戰士的榮譽
He'll abide by the honor of the duel.
一定會遵守決鬥的約定
Remember the reason why you're fighting.
想想你戰鬥的目的
You want to kill me in a duel, don't you?
你想在決鬥中打敗我，不是嗎？
For the time being,
你就暫時
consider me your adviser.
把我當成參謀吧
This is for the both of us to survive.
這樣我們兩個才能活著離開
I wanted to see the commander's duel.
我好想看老大的決鬥
I want to go out in a duel with the commander, too.
如果要死的話 我想在決鬥中被老大殺死
I'd enter Valhalla with pride.
驕傲地進入瓦爾哈拉
He's on a different level, an incarnation of the god of thunder, Thor.
他真不是普通的強
If the commander is Thor, then does that mean Prince Canute is Freyja?
如果老大是雷神索爾
A goddess!
女神！
What? It's Freyja's incarnation.
那不是芙蕾雅的化身嗎？
Take this!
接招！
Does it hurt, Thorfinn?
會痛嗎，托爾芬？
Why not abandon Askeladd
要不要乾脆放棄阿謝拉特
and surrender?
認輸啊？
Bastard!
混蛋！
Don't run away!
別跑！
Don't you know when to give up?
你不知道什麼時候該放棄嗎？
What's with you?
你怎麼會這樣？
Fight with honor to the end!
拿出尊嚴奮戰到底啊！
Are you trying to sully Thors's name?
你想毀了托爾茲的名聲嗎？
Endure it for now, Thorfinn.
暫時忍耐一下，托爾芬
Have him come to you.
讓他靠近你
It was at the Battle of Maldon.
那是在摩爾頓之戰的時候吧？
It was a vicious battle.
那場戰鬥很激烈
Everyone was severely wounded, even Thorkell.
每個人都受了重傷 托魯克爾也不例外
Just one moment.
但有一瞬間
At that moment I saw it.
就那麼一瞬間，我確實看到了
The moment the invincible Thorkell crumbled.
所向無敵的托魯克爾居然倒地了
Very good.
非常好
Make him think you've exhausted your options.
讓他以為你束手無策了
What's wrong, Thorfinn?
托爾芬，你怎麼了？
Tired of running?
逃累了嗎？
How disappointing.
真是令人失望
I figured you'd have more fighting spirit.
我還以為你會更有骨氣
Good positioning.
位置不錯
Well done, Thorfinn.
你做得很好，托爾芬
He is so lame.
結局真是令人失望
Pathetic.
太丟臉了
He just evaded.
他只會逃來逃去
Yes, Thorkell.
就是這樣，托魯克爾
Come to put an end to him.
解決掉他吧
Final moment.
再來就等
Last chance.
那一瞬間的機會
His weakness is…
他的弱點是…
Commander!
老大！
You fool! You don't have a weapon!
笨蛋，你沒有拿武器！
Thorfinn! To your right!
托爾芬，小心右邊！
Kill the brat!
殺了那個小鬼！
Damn it!
可惡！
Die, brat!
去死吧，小鬼！
Stop, you fools!
住手，你們這些笨蛋！
How dare you bastards disgrace me with your impudence?
你們這些混帳竟然讓我丟人現眼？
But Commander!
可是老大…
How dare you defile my duel with your interference!
竟然敢破壞我的決鬥！
Asgeir, you bastard.
阿斯蓋特，你這混蛋
Where is your honor as a warrior?
你身為戰士的榮譽跑哪去了？
You can begrudge me.
你可以恨我
But I will kill that boy.
但我要殺了那小子
If you're going to kill me, do it.
你要殺我的話就殺吧
But you must live!
但你必須活下去！
Who else is going to unify these 500 brutes?
不然有誰控制得了這五百頭野獸？
That is enough.
夠了
Stop this fight.
不要再打了
Those who die in this battle will die in vain.
不然在這場戰鬥中死亡的人 就白白犧牲了
It can't be.
不會吧…
Everyone has been killed.
全軍覆沒？
Askeladd's army…
阿謝拉特的軍團…
Brother!
哥！
You're alive?
你還活著？
Good man, who are you?
先生，你是哪位？
Brother.
哥…
Relentless.
簡直沒完沒了…
How could you kill each other like this?
你們怎麼可以這樣互相殘殺？
Royalty has no right to interfere in a duel.
王室無權干涉決鬥
Stay out of it, princess.
公主，別插手
In this state, this is no longer a duel.
現在這樣已經不是決鬥了
If you are the leader of a faction.
如果你是他們的領袖
You must show honor and sportsmanship.
就應該展現榮譽和戰士風範
Shut up!
閉嘴！
I am well aware without your interference!
那種事我很清楚，不用你告訴我！
Let Thorfinn go.
放了托爾芬
I've lost the duel.
這場決鬥是我輸了
You haven't lost! We interfered!
你沒輸，是我們干涉了…
Shut up, you imbeciles!
閉嘴，一群廢物！
I lost.
我輸了
Let me retain my dignity.
讓我留點尊嚴吧
Asgeir.
阿斯蓋特
Do as your commander has ordered.
照老大的話做
What a calamity.
真是不爽
I've never had a more miserable day in my 50 years on earth!
我活了50年 從沒有像今天這麼不爽過！
Drink!
拿酒來！
Hey, geezer! Now's our chance to get away.
光頭，現在是逃跑的機會
Go if you want.
你要走就走
-I'm staying. -What?
-我要留下來 -什麼？
Then what was I fighting for?
那我打成這樣是為了什麼？
Shut up and watch.
閉嘴，看清楚了
So? What do you want, Prince?
所以呢？王子，你想怎樣？
Have you casually come to arbitrate our fight?
特地跑回來勸架的嗎？
I require a sled and some provisions.
我需要雪橇和糧食
And Thorfinn and Askeladd are in my service.
還有，托爾芬和阿謝拉特是我的隨從
They're mine.
我要帶他們走
You're out of your mind.
你是笨蛋吧？
What hunter would let his prey to walk away?
哪個獵人會這麼輕易讓獵物離開？
By taking me you can secure an audience with King Sweyn.
面對斯韋恩王時 我可以當你的祕密武器
Is that what you're thinking?
你是這麼打算的吧？
Yes, Your Highness.
是的，殿下
You're valuable bait as a hostage.
你會是很有價值的誘餌和人質
Give up on the prince!
放棄王子吧
Don't get greedy!
別太貪心！
Just watch!
你看就對了！
Back away, lackey. I will not run.
給我退下，我不會逃跑
You have learned to talk like a man in such a short time.
你在這麼短的時間內 就學會怎麼大聲說話了
What happened?
發生什麼事了？
I saw Ragnar's corpse in the village we passed.
我們昨天經過那個村子 看到了拉古納爾的屍體
Thorkell.
托魯克爾
I have no value as a hostage.
我沒有當人質的價值
That is because…
因為…
my father
父王
has no love for me.
根本不愛我
My father will pass the crown to my elder brother Harald.
父王會讓哈羅德王兄繼承王位
I am insurance for brother and nothing more.
我只不過是王兄的備胎而已
Because of this, the king's retainers are squabbling for power,
但我的存在使得臣子開始勾心鬥角
and jeopardizing the foundation of the kingdom.
危害到了王國的根基
My existence is at the root of my father's troubles.
我的存在使父王的擔憂
So King Sweyn is hoping that I will kill you?
所以斯韋恩王希望我殺了你？
It's more convenient for me to die in battle than by assassination.
比起暗殺，讓我戰死比較方便
My father can wash his hands clean of his child's death.
父王就不必背負弒子的惡名
Supposing that I let you go free, where would you go?
如果我放你走，你打算去哪？
To the base of the home army in Gainsborough.
蓋恩斯伯勒的軍團大本營
To fight my father, the king.
對抗我的父王
You think you can win?
你覺得你有勝算嗎？
Good luck with that.
祝你好運
I'm only doing what I must.
我只是在做自己該做的事
Either way,
不管怎樣
my life has no value.
我的生命都毫無價值
I have heard
我見過很多說自己毫無價值的人 多到我都數不清了
Yet most cry and beg for their lives at the slighest provecation.
但只要我輕輕一碰 很多人都會哭著求饒
Are you like them too?
你也是嗎？
I hate that look.
這眼神好討厭
I've seen eyes like these before.
我看過這種眼神
What are you looking at through those eyes?
你們到底在看什麼？
What?
什麼？
They're completely silent.
突然就不說話了
Bastards.
大夥們
I, too, have a regret, though only one.
我也做過一件後悔的事
Why didn't I go with Thors back then?
我當初怎麼沒有跟托爾茲一起走？
Had I gone with him,
要是我跟他一起走
I would have learned what it means to be a true warrior.
我就會知道 成為“真正的戰士”的祕密了
Well, fighting King Sweyn changes nothing.
好吧，反正都要和斯韋恩王打
All right! I've decided!
好，我決定了
I will aid you in your fight.
我會助你一臂之力
I will accompany you.
我要追隨你
I will see for myself what you will do and who you will become.
我想親眼看看你會做出什麼事 成為什麼樣的人
But if you do something weak, I'll kill you myself.
但如果你做出窩囊的事 我會立刻殺了你
Agreed.
那好
Then from today, you shall be my retainer.
從今天起，你就是我的隨從
What? Then what are we supposed to do?
什麼？那我們該怎麼辦？
I guess we just follow the commander.
只能跟著老大啊
What's with him?
他在搞什麼？
He's still here?
他還在？
Prince Canute.
庫奴特王子
I was the one who killed Ragnar.
殺了拉古納爾的人是我
Please, cut me down.
請殺了我吧
However,
不過
if you spare my life,
如果您饒我一命
I'll be your servant
我會效忠於您
even if it costs me my life.
就算賠上性命也在所不惜
You will work Ragnar's position.
你得肩負拉古納爾的工作
That will serve as consolation.
這是對他的弔唁
Yes. I swear it.
是，遵命
Those who wish to follow me, come.
想追隨我的人就來吧
I will drag King Sweyn down from his throne.
我要把斯韋恩王拉下王座
What's with you? Don't imitate me.
你搞什麼？別學我
I'm not imitating.
我哪有學你？
I became his servant before you.
我先成為他的隨從的
In either case we should be friends.
我們還是好好相處吧
I killed all your men, but that's water under the bridge, right?
我殺光了你的手下 但事情過了就算了，對吧？
No matter what we do, everything will have to be water under the bridge.
無論如何